Mss.Ms.Coll.200
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to St. George Tucker, Williamsburg, Jan. 6, 1795; Page, John, 1744-1808
    Philadelphia, Photo.of A.L.S.with initials. 4p.and add.,end. (from original in William and Mary College.) Concerning his telegraph and comments of APS members, Peale, Vaughan. Comments on his other achievements. On politicians. Refers to Rittenhouse.
  - Letter to St. G[eorge] Tucker, Jan. 20, 1795; Page, John, 1744-1808
    Philadelphia, Photo.of A.L.S.with initials. 3p.and end. (from original in Tucker-Coleman MSS in William and Mary.) Concerning his telegraph and the disposal of it for public good. Refers to Peale's museum.
  - Certificate, no. 507, issued to Bird, Savage & Bird of London, for three shares of stock, March 16, 1795; 10" x 12"; North American Land Company
    Printed D.S. James Marshall, secretary; Robt Morris, President. 1p.
  - Letter to [Jeremy Bentham], March 30, 1795; La Rochefoucauld-Liancourt, François-Alexandre-Frédéric, duc de, 1747-1827
    Phila., A.L.S. 4p., end. In French. Comments on the state of the Philadelphia prison system. Mentions Vaughan.
  - Letter to John Nicholson, April 6, [1795]; 8-1/4x6-1/2; Claiborne, Richard
    A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Concerning the steam engine being erected by [Robert?] Patterson. Presented by Edwin Wolf,II, June 1962.
  - Stock certificate issued to James Carey, April 17, 1795; 12 1/2" x 9 1/2"; North American Land Company
    Phila., Printed D. filled in ms.,S.: James Marshall, secretary; Robt. Morris, president. 1p.
  - Letter to Messrs. Cadell & Davies, April 29, 1795; 7 1/2" x 9"; Pownall, Thomas, 1722-1805
    Bath, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Sends 50 copies of work entitled " Intellectual physicks." Instructions for distributing.
  - Dav[i]d Rittenhouse to the Treasurer of the Mint, May 6, 1795; 6 3/4" x 8 1/4"; Rittenhouse, David, 1732-1796
    Mint of the U.S., [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. A.D.S. Order to pay $26,810.45.5 to Samuel Vincent, agent for the Bank of Maryland. Presented to the A.P.S. by Mrs. William Stansfield, April 3, 1932.
  - Order to the treasurer of the mint of the U.S. to pay Samuel Vincent, May 6, 1795; 6-3/4x8-1/4; Rittenhouse, David, 1732-1796
    A.D.S. 1p.and end. Presented by Mrs. William Stansfield, April 3, 1932.
  - Certificate concerning the revenue from a still owned by Richard Poundstone, June 1, 1795; 6 3/8" x 7 1/2"; Poundstone, Richard
    Fayette County, Pennsylvania, 1 p. and endorsements. D.S.
  - Dav[i]d Rittenhouse to the Treasurer of the Mint, June 8, 1795; 6 1/2" x 8"; Rittenhouse, David, 1732-1796
    Mint of the U. S., [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. A.D.S. Order to pay $11,963.50 to John Vaughan. Presented to the A.P.S. by Mrs. William Stansfield, April 3, 1932.
  - "Check" for $200 to John Barnes., Aug. 12, 1795; Blair, John
    D.S. 1p. Document written by Samuel Meredith, Treasurer of the U.S. Eigned by Blair. Endorsed by Barnes upon receipt. Sum charged to Blairs's salary for the quarter ending June 30.
  - Letter to the Earl of Buchan, Carlisle, PA., Aug. 13, 1795; Nisbet, Charles
    Holograph copy of A.L.S. 6p. On state of American politics, economy, higher education, law profession, negro unrest. Mention Mr. Miller, Priestley, Rush, Witherspoon, Smith, Rowan, Jay and General Gunn.
  - Thomas Fitzsimons and James Yard, August 25, 1795; 8" x 9 7/8"; FitzSimons, Thomas, 1741-1811
    merchants of Philadelphia, in account current with Robert Ritchie of Paramaribo, 4 pp. and endorsement. D.S.: Robert Ritchie.
  - Patent issued to Isaac Wharton et al., for tract of land in Northumberland county, known as Mulberry Grove, formerly owned by James Wilson, Oct. 29, 1795; 20 1/2" x 11"; Pennsylvania. Commonwealth
    D.S.: Tho. Mifflin, as governor. 1p. and end. Parchment Seal.
  - Letter to Tiberius Cavallo, London, Nov. 7, 1795; Knowles, Charles Henry, Sir, 1754-1831
    A.L.S. 2p., add. and: J. Robison to T. Cavallo; [Nov. 1795], 6p. Introduces J. Robison, professor of natural philosophy and, according to Knowles'father, "one of the first Mathematicians in Europe." Mentions P. Paoli.
    On same sheet as Nov., 1795.
  - Letter to Tiberius Cavallo, Nov., 1795
    A.L. 6p. (Included with: [Sir] Cha[rle]s Henry Knowles to Tiberious Cavallo; November 7, 1795.) Explains his poor health and its affects on his mind. Seeks Cavallo's critical mind in evaluating his ideas. Describes his experiments with electricity and magnetism. Mentions Hooke and Newton.
  - Petition to [George Washington] concerning rebels of Whiskey Insurrection, [1795?]; Philadelphia. Citizens
    Photo. of D.S. by 65 ladies. 3p. Presented through Mr. Fleming from Alfred J. Liebmann; 6/8/54. Printed in part: Manuscripts,Spring, 1954: Liebmann. "Experts...",p.180.
  - Memoire politique et particulier, 1795; Littlepage, Lewis, 1762-1802
    Photostat of D. 16p. (from v.355 of Archives of Kingdom of Poland). Printed: APS Proc., v.101,no.3., pp.255-269. Presented by Curtis Carroll Davis.
  - Letter to Harriet [Mrs. Thomas B. Percival], Feb. 5, 1796; Harris, Caleb
    A.L.S. 4p. News of family and friends.
  - Letter to Sir Joseph Banks, February 12, 1796; Bentinck, William Henry Cavendish, Lord, 1774-1839
    Whitehall, Facsimile of A.L.S. 1p. Has forwarded Banks' letter of the 3rd and catalogue of curiosities and natural productions to the king. Mentions Menzies; refers to the British Museum and Kew royal gardens.
  - Letter to James McHenry, March 10, 1796; 9 3/4" x 8"; Pickering, Timothy, 1745-1829
    Phila., A.L.S. 3p. Relative to accounts of Israel Chapin while Indian agent for the Six Nations.
  - Letter to John G. E. Heckewelder, Feb. 22, 1796; Barton, Benjamin Smith, 1766-1815
    Xerox of A.L.S. 2p. and add. Asks questions concerning antiquities of the Indian: is mica verated? What is the color of the Indian at birth, etc. From original in U. of Pa Library.
  - Letter to Dr. Charles Hutton, Woolwich Common, June 16, 1796; 9-1/4x7-1/2; Maskelyne, Nevil, 1732-1811
    Greenwich, A.L.S. 3p.and add. Life of Condorcet. Thinks English mathematics is not recognized in Paris. comments on various mathematicians.
  - [Inventory of sale held] at the late dwelling house of Israel Jacobs in Providence township, Montgomery country, deceased, Dec. 21, 1796; 16" x 6 1/2"; Jacobs, Israel, 1726-1796
    by John Jacobs, executor; D. 8 leaves Presented by Seymour Adelman, Dec. 1952.
  - Commission of Samuel Bradford to be marshall of Mass. district, Dec. 22, 1796; Washington, George, 1732-1799
    D.S.: G. Washington, PResident and Timothy Pickering, Secretary of State. Certified: John Lowell. 1p. 11x15. Received from the Estate of I. Minus Hays: Feb. 20, 1967.
  - Extracts of laws of 6 florial, [1796]; 8-3/4x7; France. Laws, statutes, etc
    an 4 and 28 ventose, an 4; [1796]. D. 2p. In French.
  - List of votes given at a general election for electors of president and vice-president of the U.S., 1796
    D. 2p.
  - Letter to Baron de Kalb, January 9, 1797; Thompson, Benjamin, -- Count Rumford, -- 1753-1814.
    Munich, A.L.S. 8p. In French.
  - Letter to John Morris, Feb. 5, 1797; 8" x 13"; Morris, Robert, 1734-1806
    Hills, A.L.S. 2p. Educational advice; chemical experiments.
  - Letter to ----, Feb. 1, 1797; 9" x 7 1/4"; Rumford, Benjamin, Graf von, 1753-1814
    Munich, A.L.S. 4p., end. In French. His portrait. Prizes established by him accepted by the Royal Society of London and the Academy of Arts and Sciences of America.
  - Letter to [Etienne Geoffroy Saint-Hilaire], April 28, 1797; 9x7-1/4; Reimarus, Johann Albert Heinrich, 1729-1814
    Hamburg, A.L.S. 10p. In French. Concerning various aspects of natural history.
  - Letter to the Insurance Company of the State of Pennsylvania, June 27, 1797; Girard, Stephen, 1750-1831
    Philadelphia, Xerox of L.S. 1p.and end. Insures vessel and goods (the brig, Sally). Presented by Penna.Masons; June 29, 1971.
  - Letter to Mich[ae]l Joy, July 16, 1797
    Boston, A.L.S. 2p. Mentions his attempt "to find the exact spot where Gosnold landed in 1602." Comments on Gosnold's travels in the New England area.
  - Letterbook, with letters to Tench Francis, Thomas Truxton, etc.pertaining to ships for the navy, Aug.-Nov., 1797; Humphreys, Joshua, 1751-1838
    Photo.of A.L.S. 7p. (from glass negatives formerly in possession of Miss Frances M. Bradford.) Presented by Miss Bradford; Oct.1961.
  - General jury trials, Sept., 1797; 12 1/2" x 7 3/4"; Tilghman, William, 1756-1827
    Ms.D. 6p.
  - Letter to Rufus King, Dec. 4, 1797; 10 1/4" x 8"; McHenry, James, 1753-1816
    Phila., A.Dr. of L. 2p. and end. Relative to medals given to the Indians.
  - Letter to Jo[h]n Nicholson, Dec. 4, 1797; 7-3/4x4-3/4; Morris, Robert, 1734-1806
    A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Relates of attempts to collect from him. Presented by Morris Duane; 12/30/69.
  - Letter to James Hamilton, Carlisle, Dec. 13, 1797; 12 3/4" x 7 1/2"; Cadwallader, John
    Huntingdon, Printed L. filled in in ms. and S.; also A.N.S. 2p. and add., end. Mutilated. Promotional literature for the town of Birmingham recently laid out on the Juniata river.
  - Index florae Nazarethanae spontaneae,collecta in annis 1787 & 1788 a Saml. Kramsch. Supplemento addito anno 1797 a Christ[ia]n Dencke., 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Kramsch, Samuel, 1756-1824
    t.p., 6pp. Com. (In Latin.) Lists 311 species.
  - Letter to [Gianbattista Scandella], Jan. 24, 1798; Latrobe, Benjamin Henry, 1764-1820
    Richmond, Va., Photo.of A.L. 2p. Incomplete. (from original in Library of Congress.) Friendly letter. Concerning the Federal City. Presented by Antonio Pace; April 1963.
  - Letter to Jedediah Morse, Jan. 30, 1798; 6 1/2" x 8"; Sergeant, John, 1747-1824
    Stockbridge, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Report on the Indians.
  - Letter to Dr. [Gianbattista] Scandella, Philadelphia, Feb. 22, 1798; Latrobe, Benjamin Henry, 1764-1820
    Richmond, va., Photo.of A.L.S. 4p.,add.,end. (from original in Avery Library, Columbia University) House for Volney in Philadelphia. Wishes to move to Philadelphia and design school for Quakers. Designs for houses. Slavery in Virginia. Presented by Dr. Pace; April 1963.
  - An act for vesting in the American philosophical society the property [of the Silk company]...fifteenth day of April... one thousand seven hundred & eighty two., April 20, 1798; 10" x 16"; Pennsylvania. Laws, statutes, etc.
    D. 2p. and end. True copy, certified Seal. See Pennsylvania statutes, v.10, 1904, p.474.
  - William Pott to John Witman, April 24, 1798; 5 1/8" x 8"; Pott, William
    Rockland, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. (In Dutch).
  - Letter to J[Gian] B[attista] Scandelle, Philadelphia, April 30, [1798]; 10x8; Latrobe, Benjamin Henry, 1764-1820
    A.L.S. 3p.and add. Concerning Priestley and his writings, with comments on Volney's answer. Refers to Washington and Bishop Madison and Priestley. Refers to peter Porcupine and quotes a bon mot. Refers to Jefferson. Comments on Maclure.
  - Deed from Zachariah and Susannah Poulson to William Levis, for property on Chestnut street between 2nd and 3d streets, May 2, 1798; 20 3/4" x 25 1/2"; Poulson, Zachariah, 1761-1844
    Phila., Parchment D. S. Seals 1p. and end. ca. Presented by Seymour Adelman,Dec.1951.
  - Letter to [J. F.] Blumenbach, May 17, 1798; Banks, Joseph, Sir, 1743-1820
    I"Soho Square, A.L.S. 3p., add. Expresses thanks for ""all the things you have been so good as to Send to me."" Refers to Seybert, Edwards, Park and Rennell."
  - Samuel Jones, June 1, 1798; 5 7/8" x 8"; Jones, Samuel, 1734-1819
    comptroller of the state of New York, to ----, Albany, 1p. D.S.: Samuel Jones, Comptroller. Notice concerning $549.37.5 arrears of quit rents due on 30,000 acres of land granted to Thomas Wharton and others.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Sarah] Bache, July 23, 1798; Hill, Henry, 1737-1828
    Phila., Photostat of c. of L. 1p. From copy in Yale university library. FILM54-Family FRAME 7
  - Journals, [July, 1798, 1801]; 11" x 8 1/2"; Pierce, John
    Typed D. 2 pieces Transcribed from the originals in the possession of Society of Friends Record office, 3d & Arch Streets, by George Snyderman, 1956.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Robinson, London, Oct. 14, 1798; 11x8-1/2; Withering, William, 1741-1799
    Edgbaston, Typed L. 2p. Copy. Xerox copy. Expenses for publication of botany. Will forward microscopes. On same sheet with letter from Withering to Rathbone, Feb. 16, 1781.
  - Account of journey to the Seneca nation, 1798-1799; 8x5-1/2; Jackson, Halliday, 1771-1835
    A.D. lvol.consisting of 181p. Printed (from entirely different source and copy): ed.by A.F.C.Wallace.Penna. History,Penna.Hist.Ass'n. vol.19,nos.2 and 3.
    Not Found: 1/13/2011
  - Letter to George Fox, Jan. 24, 1799; 8" x 9 3/4"; Smith, Lambert
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Solicits Fox's vote for Richard Gittings as director in the office of discount and deposit of U.S. Bank. FILM54-57 FRAME 124
  - Letter to James Hamilton, Carlisle, Feb.1, 1799; 9" x 7 1/2"; Cadwallader, John
    Huntingdon, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. Sale of lots in Birmingham; distributed handbills, copy enclosed, to encourage settlers.
  - Letter to Isaiah Thomas, Worcester, Mass., Feb. 5, 1799; 10-1/2x6-1/4; Williams, Samuel, 1743-1817
    Rutland, Vt., Photo.of A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. (from original in Diederich Collection, 139 Dh, University of Amsterdam Library.) Thomas' farm is vacant. His history of Vermont could be reprinted.
  - Letter to John Harris, Feb. 15, 1799; 10x7-3/4; McHenry, James, 1753-1816
    War Department, L.S.: James McHenry and Samuel Hodgdon. 1p. and end. Authorizes U.S. flag for Cherokee nation.
  - Letter to Benjamin Vaughan, March 8, 1799; Rush, Benjamin, 1746-1813
    Photo. of A.L.S. 2p. and add. Concerning his publications. Medicine. From original in possession of Mrs. Frances Valughan Finletter.
  - Letter to James Lingan, M. Waring and John Mason, George Town, Md., March 15, 1799; 9 1/2" x 8"; Craik, William
    Phila., A.L.S. 9p. and add. end. Removal of the capital to Washington; utilization of George Town for federal offices.
  - Letter to [Christian Hendrik] Persoon, April 8, 1799; 11-3/4x8-1/4; Banks, Joseph, 1743-1820
    London, Photo.of A.L.S. 3p.and add. enc.by Dryander. (from original in Universiteitsbibliotheek, Leiden.) Concerning post of botanist at Capetown and the lack of pay there. Botany and fungi. Refers to Blumenbach.
  - Letter to Mrs. R[ichard, i.e. Sarah] Bache, May 16, 1799; Francis, Anne
    Phila., Photostat of c. of L. 2p. From copy in Yale university library. FILM 54-family FRAME 8
  - Letter to Henry Christophe, June 29, 1799; Louverture, Toussaint
    A.L.S. 1p., add. and end. In French. Enclosed originally in: Gideon H. Hollister to Hamilton Fish; April 5, 1869. Presented by the Estate of Warwick Potter; 4/26/73
  - Power of attorney to John Steele to administer estate of James Campbell in the Mississippi territory, July 15, 1799; 7 3/4" x 12 3/4"; Dunbar, William, 1749-1810
    A.D.S: William Dunbar, Judge of Probate. 1p. Seal
  - Letter to ----, October 10, 1799; 8 1/4" x 10"; La Rochefoucauld-Liancourt, François-Alexandre-Frédéric, duc de, 1747-1827
    A.L.S. 1p. "Duplicate" Relates to the sale of his Travels through N.A., 75 copies of which are being sent to [America ?].
  - Jury list for second period, Dec. 9, Nov. 8, 1799; Philadelphia. Court
    Printed D. filled in in ms. 1p. and end. by Wm. Tilghman (?).
  - Letter to Ja[me]s Anderson, Dec. 13, 1799; Washington, George, 1732-1799
    Mount Vernon, Facsimile of A.L.S. 1p. From original in Dreer collection in the Historical society of Pennsylvania; on same sheet is provenance of letter. Presented by Abigail D. Dreer, May 28, 1900.
  - Letter to Citoyen Vaume, docteur en medicine..., Dec. 27, 1799; Lalande, Joseph Jérôme Le Français de, 1732-1807
    In French, Includes engraving of Lalande. Congratulates Vaume on his imporant book.
  - Petition to [John Adams,] president of the U.S., [1799]; 12-3/4x7-3/4; Woodrow, Susannah S.
    from sundry female inhabitants of Philadelphia, asking that prisoners of Fries rebellion be released; [ca.1799]. D.S.by Susannah S. Woodrow and 71 others. 4p. Presented by A.J.Liebmann; 6/17/54.
  - Letter to Dr. Marcet, Jan. 1, 1800; Playfair, John, 1748-1819
    Edinburgh, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Enclosure for Mr. Pictet of Geneva. Congratulations his marriage.
  - Letter to T. Davis, Fort Wilkinson, Jan. 24, 1800; Gaither, Henry, 1751-1811
    A.L.S. 4p. Discusses the work of Colonel Hawkins among the Creek Indians and the capture of William Bowles and his escape to Florida. Gift of Minnesota Historical Society, 10/29/1990
  - Letter to Wm. Allen, March 20, 1800; Greene, Ray
    Phila., Photostat of A.L.S. 1p. The application for his son's William Henry, appointment as midshipman in the U.S. Navy is under consideration. From original in possession of the Henry E. Huntington library.
  - Letter to the [U.S.] Secretaries of State, Treasury, War, Navy & Attorney General, April 23, 1800; 8 1/4" x 9 3/4"; Adams, John, 1735-1826
    Philadelphia, L.S. 4p., end. Proposal in re government printer and an official gazette. Printed: Adam's Life and works, v.9,50.
  - Letter to John Maitland, April 2, 1800; Banks, Joseph, Sir, 1743-1820
    A.L. 1p.and add.and end. Concerning buffaloes.
  - Letter to [William Sotheby], April 5, 1800; Banks, Joseph, Sir, 1743-1820
    A.L.S. 2p. Concerning his poetry.
  - Letter to [James] McHenry, April 28, 1800; 8 1/2" x 10 1/4"; Chase, Samuel, 1741-1811
    [ca.]. A(?)L. 2p. and add., end. Opinion on president's proposal for an official printer and gazette. FILM 403 FRAME 182
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l chase, April 28, 1800; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; M'Henry, James, 1785-1845
    A.Dr. of L.S. 3p. and end. Asks his opinion about the president's proposal in re official printer and gazette. FILM 403 FRAME 183
  - Letter to George Wescott, Philadelphia, May 1, 1800; Coxe, Tench, 1755-1824
    Land Office. A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. Concerning land office business.
  - The young lady's address to piety, Sept. 3, 1800
    A.D. 1p. Poem in ryming couplets. Found with: B:H244i.2 Harrison, Johseph. The iron worker and king Solomon. Phila., 1869.
  - Letter to [Thomas?] Webster, London, Sept. 8, 1800; 8x6-1/2; Rumford, Benjamin, Graf von, 1753-1814
    Morpeth, A.L.S. 2p.and add. If he wants the post as assistant in natural philosophy at the Royal Institution, recommends contacting Dr. Garnett, for recommendation.
  - Vouchers for duties paid, in Pennsylvania, on carriages, 1800; U.S. Collector of revenue
    Printed Ds. filled in in ms. 23 items and label. Various sizes.
  - Commission to Samuel Bradford to be marshall of Mass. district, December 22, 1800
    D.S. John Adams, President and J. Marshal, Secretary of State. Certified: John Lowell. 1p.
    See oversize box.
  - Abstract of a meteorological register kept at the Cape of Good Hope..., 1800-1805; 8" x 10"; Elmslie, John
    D. 20 leaves.
  - Accounts of Charles Thomas and William Pritchard for stone used on bridge, 1801; 8x13-1/2; Morris, Robert, 1734-1806
    D. 1p.and end.
  - Letter to [Sir William] Herschel, Windsor, Jan. 12, 1801; 9x7-1/4; Rumford, Benjamin, Graf von, 1753-1814
    Royal Institution, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Asks for reprints from the royal society publications on calorific rays.
  - Letter to C[hristian] H[endrik] Persoon, Feb. 8, 1801; 9x7-1/2; Banks, Joseph, 1743-1820
    London, Photo.of A.L.S. 3p.and add. (from original in Universiteitsbibliotheek, Leiden.) Would like for him to become botanist for Kew at the Cape of Good Hope, and collect specimens.
  - Account of Geo[rge] Logan, Prestly Carr Lane and John Hunn(?) to deal with the Delaware legislature concerning the canal, Feb. 26, 1801; 12x8-1/4; Pennsylvania
    Lancaster. D.S.: Jas. Trimble, Dep.Secy.and Jno. Donaldson, compt.gen. 1p.
  - Receipts for stamped paper, Feb. 27-June 15, 1801; Graeff, Jacob
    D.S. 9 leaves. Various sizes.
  - Letter to ---, May 7, 1801; Herschel, William, Sir, 1738-1822
    Slough; A.L.S. 1p. Adds to his paper concerning solar rays on plants before publication in Philosophical Transactions, and needs his meterological observations.
  - Account with Benjamin Rush, Jan.30-April 27,1801, July 14, 1801; 15 1/2" x 13"; Hall, John. Estate of
    Ms.D. 1p. and end.
  - Letter to David Lewis and Charles Thomas, Aug. 11, 1801; 5-3/4x8-3/4; Morris, Robert, 1734-1806
    A.L.S. 1p. Concerning stone for bridge over the Schuylkill.
  - Journal, Aug. - Sept., 1801; Pierce, John
  - W(illia)m Seaton to Peter Muhlenberg, November 14, 1801; 6 3/8" x 7 7/8"; Seaton, William
    Muddy Creek, Greene County, 1p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Mr. Seaton will forward records and books to Mr. Muhlenberg.
  - Etat de distribtion des droits ... moi Frimaire an dix ..., Nov. (?), 1801; Institut de France. Académie des sciences morales et politiques.
    1 sheet, 2 pcs.
  - Course of lecture on physics, Dec. (?), [1801]; Lefèvre, Jean-Jacques, 1779-1858
    24p.
  - Letter to Rev. Dr. Beach, Dec. 16, 1801; 9x8; Mitchill, Samuel L. (Samuel Latham), 1764-1831
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Asks that he submit the enclosed paper to the trustees of Columbia college.
  - Letter to Thomas [Peters] Smith, Dec. 30, 1801; 13x8, 10x8; Watt, James, 1769-1848
    Soho, A.L.S. 4p.,add.and 1 leaf docketed by J.Vaughan. Lists minerals forwarded. Friendly letter. When found in 1959, this item was mounted in scrapbook kept by J.Vaughan. For other material in scrapbook,see: T.P.Smith. List of minerals...;JUne-Nov.1800 [1801].
  - List of minerals sent to Thomas P. Smith, to which is added a list sent by Gillet-Laumont, [1801]; 9x7; Tonnellier,
    D.S. 8p.and 2 mounting leaves, docketed in hand of J.Vaughan. In French. When found in 1959, this item was mounted in scrapbook kept by J.Vaughan. For other material in scrapbook, see: T.P.Smith. List of minerals...;June-Nov. 1800 [1801].
  - Letter to Timothy Matlack, Jan. 24, 1802; 12x7; Bryan, Guy
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p.and add. Sends good brown cloth to Mr. Matlack. Opinion of legislature regarding the charter for "our Improving Company."
  - Letter to ---, Jan. 30, 1802; Herschel, William, Sir, 1738-1822
    Slough; A.L.S. 2p. "Rediscovery of Mr. Piazzi's planet." Astronomy. Refers to Royal Society.
  - List of minerals sent to J[ames] Watt, jr, April 22, 1802; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Smith, Thomas P. (Thomas Peters), 1777 or 8-1802
    2 florial An X A.D. 4p.,end.by J.Vaughan. For sheet on which this was mounted, see: J.Watt to Smith; Dec.30,1801. When found in 1959, this item was in scrapbook kept by J.Vaughan. For other material in scrapbook, see: T.P.Smith. List of minerals...;June-Nov.1800 [1801]
  - Letters to --, May 15, June 1, 1802
    22p and end. Copies. Describes the people, morals, etc. of the United States. Translated from: L'Amerique du Nord; ou, le Correspondant des Etats-Unis.
  - Letter to David Hosack, New York, May 22, 1802; Dick, Elisha Cullen, 1762-1825
    Asks for advice on use of "oxygen air" in treating diseases, esp. in case of dyspepsia caused by excessive use of laudanum. Comments on pneumatic medicine.
  - W[illia]m Dunbar to C. Ross, June 12, 1802; 7 3/4" x 9 1/2"; Dunbar, William, 1749-1810
    Natchez, 1 p. and endorsement. L. Unsigned. Copy. Extract only. Information regarding vaccination to be communicated to Mr. [John?] Vaughan.
  - Letter to "My dear Lord", July 25, 1802; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Banks, Joseph, 1743-1820
    A.L.S. 1p. Draft. His sheep cost too much. On same sheet with letter from ---- to Sir Joseph Banks; July 25, 1802.
  - Letter to [My dear Lord], July 29, 1802; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Banks, Joseph, 1743-1820
    A.L.S. 1p. Draft. Concerning purchase of sheep. On same sheet as letter from ---- to Sir Joseph Banks; July 25, 1802.
  - Letter to [M. Perigaux, banckers;], July 30, 1802; 9-1/2x7-3/4; Priestley, Joseph, 1733-1804